themeparktourist.com 2019-04-26

# Privacy & Cookies Policy | Theme Park Tourist

## General

In this Cookies Statement and Privacy Policy Statement, "We", "Us" and "Our" mean Theme Park Tourist. Our address is Theme Park Tourist, 13 Gladstone Road, Ipswich, Suffolk, IP3 8AT.

When we refer to Our website we are referring to any website in the domain themeparktourist.com and the website www.themeparktourist.com.

## Cookies

### What are cookies?

Cookies are one of the building blocks of most websites for enhancing the user experience of the website visitor. These small text files on users’ computers allow websites to store information.

Cookies can allow websites to remember that a user is logged in, what they have added to their shopping basket and the current ‘state’ of a webpage. They are also used to produce targeted advertising based on users’ behaviour and assist statistics packages such as Google Analytics.

### Our use of cookies

We may use cookies to deliver a better and more personalised interaction/user experience. They enable Us to recognise you when you return to Our website by storing information about your preferences.

We use them to remember that you are logged in after you enter your username and password and then navigate to a different page. They also enable Us to generate statistics about the number of visitors We have and how they use Our websites and the internet – this allows Us to constantly improve Our website and services.

For more information about how We use cookies please see the Definition of Cookies and their function section below.

### Managing cookies

You can set your browser to reject Our cookies if you wish, but this might restrict your use of Our and other websites. For instructions on deleting or controlling cookies please consult your browser help section or see [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Definition of cookies and their function

**i. Session cookies**

These are temporary cookie files, which are erased when you close your browser. They are used to store your browsing information while you are using Our websites and will be active until you leave the website and close your browser.

**ii. Persistent cookies**

Persistent cookies help Us remember your information and settings for any future visits. This results in faster and more convenient access. On your first visit, the website is presented in default mode. During your visit, you select your preferences and these preferences are remembered, through the use of the persistent cookie, for the next time you visit the website. A persistent cookie enables a website to remember you on subsequent visits, speeding up or enhancing your experience of services or functions offered.

**iii. CMS specific - session cookies**

These types of cookies are placed by Our content management software (CMS) to remember whether your browser has JavaScript enabled.

**iv. CMS specific - persistent cookies**

These types of cookies are placed by our content management software (CMS) to remember your display preferences.

**v. Google Analytics (3rd party) cookies**

These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use Our websites. We use the information to compile reports and to help improve the website. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the website, where visitors have come to the website from and the pages they visited.

An overview of privacy at Google can be found here <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

Google Analytics data is completely anonymised, and this data is kept for 50 months from the last visit you have made to Theme Park Tourist. If you have any questions please contact our Data Controller at [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com).

**vi. Google Ads**

Google Ad Manager uses a cookie to be able to manage the frequency you see each advert.

**vii. JavaScript code that sets cookies**

JavaScript code can also be used to set cookies. These uses of cookies can be conditional, e.g. only activated when the user clicks on a particular page item or performs a particular action, or they can be set as soon as a page is visited.

**viii. Third party cookies**

To improve your experience of using Our website, We sometimes embed content or functionality from third party websites. Pages with this embedded content may present cookies from these websites. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the relevant third party website for more information about these. Examples of such third party cookies are:

YouTube: Clicking on an embedded YouTube video may set a cookie on your computer, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode. To find out more please visit YouTube’s embedding videos information page.

Twitter: We may use Twitter functionality to allow you to easily tweet links to our content. Navigating to pages with this functionality may embed a cookie on your computer. The Twitter privacy policy can be found at <https://twitter.com/en/privacy>.

### Cookies in use

For Drupal CMS:

ccShowCookieIcon | Implemented by the Cookie Control module and records whether or not to show the Cookie Control icon – expiry 90 days  
---|---  
has_js | Determines whether or not JavaScript is enabled so that Drupal can more efficiently perform operations to enhance the user experience – expiry is end of session on browser/tab close.  
_cookiecontrol | Implemented by the Cookie Control module and records the fact that you as a user have agreed to accept cookies from this site – expiry 90 days  
SESS | Only set when logged in - Identifies the user's session  
Drupal.toolbar.collapsed | Only set when logged in - Determines the display preference of the toolbar for the user  
  
For basic Google Analytics:

_gat | Cookies set by Google Analytics and is used to throttle requests and has an expiration of 1-minute  
---|---  
_ga | Cookie set by Google Analytics and is used to distinguish users and has an expiration of 2-years  
_gid | Cookie set by Google Analytics and is used to distinguish users and has an expiration of 24-hours  
_gac_  
| Contains campaign related information for the user. If you have linked your Google Analytics and AdWords accounts, AdWords website conversion tags will read this cookie unless you opt-out  
  
For Google Analytics Tracking:

__utma | Used to distinguish users and sessions. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utma cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics.  
---|---  
__utmt | Used to throttle request rate  
__utmb | Used to determine new sessions/visits. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and no existing __utmb cookies exists. The cookie is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics  
__utmc | Set for interoperability with urchin.js. Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether the user was in a new session/visit  
__utmz | Stores the traffic source or campaign that explains how the user reached your site. The cookie is created when the javascript library executes and is updated every time data is sent to Google Analytics  
  
To read the full cookie declaration visit <https://www.cookiebot.com/goto/cookie-declaration/>

The Cookie Declaration contains the following elements:

1\. A standard introduction text informing the website users about the use of cookies 

2\. The user can see his current consent (what categories of cookies consent has been given for), change his consent or completely withdraw his consent. If the user clicks ‘change your consent’ or ‘withdraw your consent’ the cookie consent banner will re-appear.

3\. Information about when the Cookie Declaration was last updated. This date is automatically updated when a scan has been performed on the website.

4\. A list of all the cookies and trackers in use on the website – categorized in Necessary, Preferences, Statistics and Marketing - along with purpose descriptions and additional information. This information is automatically drawn from the latest scan report for your website and is automatically updated with each new scan.

## THEME PARK TOURIST Privacy Policy

We aim to make this privacy policy as easy to understand as possible. However, if there is anything that doesn't make sense to you, please don't hesitate to contact us.

We are firmly committed to respecting your privacy and complying with applicable data protection and privacy laws.

We have provided this Privacy Policy Statement to help you understand how We collect, use and protect your information when you visit/use Our website and when you generally use Our products and services. If you do submit personal information by ordering products, services or completing a web form registration, for example, you can be assured that We will only use your personal information for the purpose intended, as illustrated below.

We wish to help you make informed decisions, so please take a few moments to read the sections below and learn how We use your personal information.

### Personal information collection

We endeavour to collect and use your personal information only with your knowledge and consent.

On Our website, We may collect your personal information for the following:

  * Product & Services Sales
  * General Enquiries
  * Mailing List Sign-Ups
  * Submit a Job Application
  * Questionnaires or Surveys

The type of personal information We collect could include, for example, your name and postal address, date of birth, telephone number, email address, location, country, biography, website you are linked to or other general information such as [lifestyle information collected in surveys or questionnaires].

We will not process any personal data collected through the Website unless We have first told you that We are going to do so, and it is clear how We will use it.

### Non-Personal Information Collection

We may collect information about the software on your computer (your browser version etc.) and your IP address (your connection with the internet) in order to improve your interaction with the Website. This may happen automatically without you being aware of it.

We may use cookies (small text files which We and other website operators store on your computer when you visit our websites) to deliver a better and more personalised interaction. They enable Us to recognise you when you return to the Website, store information about your preferences, and improve the way your searches are processed. This helps Us to better manage and develop Our website, to provide you with a more enjoyable, customised service and experience in the future, and to help Us develop and deliver better products and services tailored to your individual interests and needs.

Cookies also enable Us to generate statistics about the number of visitors We have and how they use the Website and the internet to improve the service We provide. You can set your browser to reject Our cookies if you wish (you should consult your browser help section for details), but this might restrict your use of the Website and other websites. For more information about cookies, please see our cookies statement.

From time to time, if you consented accordingly We may also store and use your information to contact you for market research and marketing purposes. We may contact you by email.

### How will we use your information?

We use personal data for the following purposes:

  * Processing orders.
  * Managing or administering your account.
  * To provide you with the services you have requested through the Website.
  * Responding to complaints or account enquiries.
  * To respond to requests for information submitted by you on the website.
  * For research purposes and to improve the services We offer.
  * In order to comply with Our legal obligations.
  * In order to protect Our contractual and other rights. For example, we may pass your details onto a third party should We believe that you have used another person's credit card fraudulently.

We may also undertake market and product analysis based on your use of Our services and products and contact you with information about new developments, products, services and special offers by post, telephone and automated means such as Email and the internet (subject to any preferences expressed by you).

If you have consented to receive details of products and services, events and training or have signed up to Our newsletter, you can contact Us at any time to have your details removed from lists used by Us for any or all of those purposes.

To update your marketing preferences please email [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com) using the email address you registered with and, if applicable, quote your account number in the body of the email and tell Us what you want Us to do - i.e. 'I wish to opt out of receiving your newsletter’.

### Disclosure of Your Personal Data

We will not sell or pass your personal information to third parties, unless you have given Us permission or unless it is strictly necessary to deliver products or services ordered or used by you and you are notified beforehand.

For example, we may disclose your data to a credit card company to validate your credit card details and obtain payment when you buy a product or service.  
We may be obliged to disclose personal data to a third party if We have a legal or regulatory obligation to do so, for example to comply with a court order, or meet obligations in accordance with applicable law.

### Google Analytics

We are continuously striving to improve our services. To help us find out about what works and what doesn't work on our website, we use Google Analytics, an anonymous analytics service provided by Google which tracks and reports website traffic. Google Analytics does not store any personally identifiable information, this is clearly stated in their terms and conditions. <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>

For more information on how Google uses and stores your data see: [https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008](https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008)

Anonymised reporting data is retained for a period of [14 months]. When data reaches the end of the retention period, it is deleted automatically on a monthly basis.

By accepting the terms of this policy, you are agreeing to the terms and conditions of Google Analytics. <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en>

### Advertisers on the site through OKO

We use an advertising agency to manage our advertising. These are the relevant documents and policies we have been given by them to explain how they use data. If you have any questions please contact our Data Protection Officer at [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com)

  * <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>
  * [https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/2839090?hl=en&ref_topic=7395141](https://support.google.com/dfp_premium/answer/2839090?hl=en&ref_topic=7395141)
  * <https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

### Sovrn/OnScroll

  * <https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy-eu>
  * <https://www.sovrn.com/about-our-cookies/>

### Taboola

This website uses Taboola's content discovery technology to recommend to you other online content that you may be interested in. To make these recommendations, Taboola collects information about your device and your behaviour on this website (and other partnering websites) using cookies and similar technologies. To learn more, see Taboola's privacy policy or click here to opt-out.

### Social media, blogs, reviews

Any social media posts or comments you send to Us (on Our Facebook page, for instance) will be shared under the terms of the relevant social media platform (e.g. Facebook / Twitter) on which they are written and could be made public.

Other people, not Us, control these platforms. We are not responsible for this kind of sharing. We recommend you should review the terms and conditions and privacy policies of the social media platforms you use. That way, you will understand how they will use your information, what information relating to you they will place in the public domain, and how you can stop them from doing so if you are unhappy about it.

Any blog, review or other posts or comments you make about Us, Our products and services on any of Our blogs, reviews or user community services will be shared with all other members of that service and the public at large.

Any comments you make on these services and on social media in general must be not offensive, insulting or defamatory. You are responsible for ensuring that any comments you make comply with any relevant policy on acceptable use of those services.

### How long do we keep your information for?

To make sure We meet Our legal data protection and privacy obligations, We only hold on to your information for as long as We actually need it for the purposes We acquired it for in the first place.

In most cases, this means We will keep your information for as long as you continue to use Our services and are deemed a client, and for a reasonable period of time afterwards if you stop doing so, to see if We can persuade you to come back to Us.

After that We will delete it other than where We lawfully can keep any data for audit or legal reasons.

We shall keep your personal information on Our database for not longer than [5] year/s from receipt, subject to an individual’s right to unsubscribe or be forgotten at any time.

### Requesting removal of your information

You can write to Us at any time to request removal of the personal information We may hold about you. Please write to: [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com) or the Data Protection Officer, Natalie Sim, Theme Park Tourist, 13 Gladstone Road, Ipswich, Suffolk, IP3 8AT.

Please quote your name and address together with your account number, if relevant. We would be grateful if could also provide brief details of why you wish to have your details removed from Our database, however, this is not a requirement.

We will not make any charge for removing any personal information We hold about you.

We may take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before removing the personal information We may hold about you, this is for your security.

### Access to your information

You can write to Us at any time to obtain details of the personal information We may hold about you. Please write to: [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com) or the Data Protection Officer, Natalie Sim, Theme Park Tourist, 13 Gladstone Road, Ipswich, Suffolk, IP3 8AT.

Please quote your name and address together with your account number, if relevant. We would be grateful if could also provide brief details of what information you want a copy of - this will help Us to more readily locate your information.

We will not make any charge for providing you with a copy of the personal information We hold about you.

We will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any personal information We may hold about you.

### Information Security

We recognise that people are becoming increasingly concerned about how companies protect personal information from misuse and abuse and about privacy in general. 

All personal data that you supply Us with from Our website is stored on servers provided by Our hosting provider. We understand that Our hosting provider (SIRUSS Ltd) only employs servers sited in data centres that have the highest level of security accreditation at the time of implementation. For your protection, We never store any payment details and where possible We store personal data such as passwords, encrypted.

We use industry standard TLS certificates to provide encryption of data in transit, for example, all access to Our website is covered by HTTPS.

Please also be aware that communications over the Internet, such as emails, are not secure unless they have been encrypted. Your communications may route through a number of countries before being delivered - this is the nature of the World Wide Web/Internet. We cannot accept responsibility for any unauthorised access or loss of personal information that is beyond Our control.

### Privacy Policy Support

We reserve the right to amend or modify this Privacy Policy Statement at any time and in response to changes in applicable data protection and privacy legislation. Please check back here and review this document to ensure you are conversant and in agreement with Our current Privacy Policy.

We operate an open and transparent privacy policy. If you have any enquiry about Our privacy policy or data collection practices, please write to: [natalie@themeparktourist.com](mailto:natalie@themeparktourist.com) or the Data Protection Officer, Natalie Sim, Theme Park Tourist, 13 Gladstone Road, Ipswich, Suffolk, IP3 8AT.

You can find out more about your rights from the Information Commissioner, who regulates data protection and privacy. The Information Commissioner's website is <https://ico.org.uk/>.

### Submitted content

Theme Park Tourist reserves the right to republish any comments or articles submitted to it in any medium at any time.
